# Nahida Islam





nahida\_1994@hotmail.com 💟



www.linkedin.com/in/nahida-islam/ in

Highly motivated IT professional with experience working on several different projects and applications, during a 5-year IT education at KTH. I like to meet customer requirements with innovative solutions that maximize efficiency and exceed capability targets. I have a great passion for learning new things, and it is important for me to continuously develop my skills and grow as a developer as well as a designer. I want to have a position where I can feel I am part of a team that is working together and contribute to the company's future. I have a great interest in sustainability and open to work with companies who values sustainability. I am eager to put my theoretical knowledge into practice as well as share my knowledge.

For more examples of projects in detail, visit my portfolio.

For some examples of programming projects and applications I have worked on, visit my Github.

## **Professional Experiences**

2020 - 2020

Video Encoder (short-term)/ Postnord

Working independently to ensure that letters / packages reach the right person by sorting them via different computer systems and the required sorting rules. The work requires a high demand on focus and accuracy throughout the work shifts.

2016 - 2020

#### 1st line NOC-Operator/Teracom AB

Problem-solving and customer contact are two lead words for this role. Teracom broadcasts TV and radio in Sweden and supplies data services. The role of a NOC operator includes monitoring of networks, troubleshooting, and dispatch for service business. The work requires an eye for accuracy and planning as well as the ability to make quick decisions under pressured situations.

JAN 2020 - JUN 2020

#### Master's thesis/ CERO

An user-centered evaluation of the CERO simulation tool. The work includes interviweing customers, prototyping a potential design and lastly testing the produced design. During this work I experienced the whole cycle of UX design.

The thesis report can be viewed in Diva KTH: Thesis report

2016 - 2016

#### Group leader/ Teklafestival (KTH)

A group of students was assigned to me. My job was to navigate the group to different places and perform fun tasks with them. This gave me a good insight into leading a group.

#### Preschool teacher/Sätra Förskolan

A summer job where I worked with children from 2 years to 5 years old.

## **Competencies**

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

- HTML CSS & JAVASCRIPT
- REACT.JS, Gatsby

#### **PROTOTYPING TOOLS**

- Figma
- Sketch
- Adobe XD
- Adobe illustrator

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

- JAVA
- C, C#
- QUERY LANGUAGE: XQUERY

#### **OTHER COMPETENCIES**

- UNITY 3D
- BLENDER
- MICROSOFT ACCESS, DATABASE MANAGEMENT
- DIA, ASTAH, XQUISITOR
- MYSQL

#### **OPERATIVE SYSTEM**

- WINDOWS 7 WINDOWS 10
- LINUX (KUBUNTU)

### **Education**

2014-2020

## Degree programme in Information and Communication Technology/ Royal Institute of Technology

The education provided a broad knowledge in IT. I have taken courses in various technical areas such as software programming, web development, human-computer interaction, graphics and UX design.

## Languages

**BENGALI** 

MOTHER TONGUE.

**SWEDISH** VERY GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN WRITTEN AND SPOKEN.

**ENGLISH** VERY GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN WRITTEN AND SPOKEN.

HINDI GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN SPOKEN ONLY.

URDU GOOD KNOWLEDGE IN SPOKEN ONLY.

## **Driving license**

Driving license B 2018